okay so this one's frankly a bit
challenging
so we'll see let's see if I can pull it
off and B if it lands so the idea here
is I want to combine a couple of
different ideas together one is I want
to take some of the stuff that was done
in the in the context of the war on
sense-making and then I want to add in a
few more pieces so here's what we're
looking at here's my proposition over
the past hundred years or so there has
been a combination of things going on
where on the one hand there has been a
sophisticated collective innovation in
how to attack human sense-making so I'm
going to call this techniques of
manipulation in control or mimetic
warfare is even better than the medic
warfare all right so we've gone from
kind of the invention of the musket to
the invention of the nuclear bomb in the
context of memetic warfare I mean if
that's a metaphor right we invented
telling lies at the schoolyard to sort
of sophisticated internet AI driven
manipulation of the human psyche of
cognitive system and we did it over the
past century or so okay that's one piece
second piece is things that are invented
and in particular things that are social
techniques have this characteristic of
propagating all right so techniques that
were cutting edge and very narrowly held
and say like major state intelligence
agencies in the 70s propagated out into
the social field until they are
effectively now ubiquitously used by a
13 year olds and this is because they've
become part of the environment that
become part of the developmental
universe you know you're watching TV and
you're being manipulated by techniques
that were originally developed in World
War two to modify soldiers you just
can't help it the people who are
literally making the TV shows either
created those techniques or affected by
those techniques and they influenced the
way that they're creating commercials or
they're creating TV so your mind is now
a dad
that niche and you're absorbing it as
being both a hostile act is also how you
do stuff okay and then and then you grow
up and you become a producer of you know
social media and and you bring all the
innovations that you've brought in your
cohort have brought interacting with
each other in this new milieu and
inflict that on the next generation of
kids who absorb that okay so if you take
these two pieces together the
proposition is that we have particularly
among kids born in the Molino so kids
born after in the 80s and later and by
the way this is not strictly that like
it's more so the younger you get because
it is just a continuing presence in the
social field a it highly internalized
how the unconscious hyper skillfulness
in super advanced techniques of
psychological warfare so it's not like
psyops psyops are sort of everything now
all minds have been have internalized
siop and are good at it
and by the way I suspect below a certain
age threshold you may in fact have a
difficulty interacting with any kind of
human interaction other than it is a
PSYOP all right okay third monocropping
mimetic monocropping
so one of the things that happened in
Western culture was in the 60 the late
60s there was a separation of
neurocognitive and cultural topologies
so broadly speaking liberals the left
people who had the neurology and the
cognitive bias in the direction of those
particular cultural and dispositional
states moved into the culture industries
so they moved into teaching and academia
they moved into a media and
entertainment and news and journalism
and by the way finance and conservative
mindsets moved into different subsets of
the the environment they moved into the
military
- real real businesslike logistics and
energy and things like that and and by
the way these groups also then begin to
migrate transportation and different
kinds of economics means meant that you
said second a migration of people from
who you may be used to have to be with
other type ologies concentrating and
separating so you got lots of blue
cities that suddenly became just blue
cities blue everywhere and lots of red
rural environments became red rural
environments red everywhere and these
are cultural mono crops and that's the
the point here is that we we created
over now almost three generations a
hyper selective environment where
everybody who you interact with more or
less has kind of the same deep
neurological and cognitive biases in
terms of how you interact with what
reality is
so you've got these places that are just
deep blue in always quizzes that are
deep red in always okay fourth the
evolutionary niche of mind viruses so we
have an environment where we have a
cohort of people a whole set of
demographics that are hyper skilled at
generating mind viruses engaging in
psyops and manipulating each other and
creating constructs that manipulate we
have cultural mono crops where there is
now minds that are separated from the
ordinary human baseline interactions so
you can actually engineer mind viruses
they're hyper selected just four blue
minds and you can engineer mind viruses
that are high precise adjust for read
minds and they'll be much more
successful because they don't have
hybrid vigor it's just like any other
mono crop hyper vulnerable to parasites
that it is that are optimized for that
niche and and of course we have been
progressing in our collective capacity
to Jack each other's minds and out for
four generations so here we are
something seems to have happened whereby
a my virus and I'm just gonna call this
now the mind rise I'm gonna divide the
world when I call one thing to my
embarrassment other thing the cytokine
storm just kind of create their
difference
and I think there was a reality that
there's a causal relationship so we have
a mind virus which seems to be highly
connected to a lot of the techniques
that were extremely successful in Maoism
and the Chinese Revolution I'm not quite
sure exactly why it might be convergent
evolution those particular techniques of
minimization and gaslighting and
struggle sessions and stuff like that
are the right ones I could just nach
they're the ones that are most effective
at capturing blue mind it may be that
because you know the the the conflict
that happened in China and frankly
happened around the whole world during
that period of time found a niche in
blue minds was able to upregulate
created enough strength to sort of win
in the Chinese Revolution and then in
the context of that niche optimized and
then it actually was able to cross
fertilize like the the actual
optimization of Maoism in China for the
Chinese knees created a hyper effective
virus then then left into a global
pandemic and found fertile soil in other
blue territories that were medically and
neurologically similar I'm not quite
sure
right the point is I'm not sure but what
I am proposing is that we have that and
we have a mind virus that was optimized
and has a lot of Maoist characteristics
and it's found itself in a huge niche
like this beautiful beautiful blue mind
mono crop where you know kids who come
into universities for example who have
been trained through kin from
kindergarten to university to be super
vulnerable to and receptive to the
entire techniques and architectures of
academia to receive input and then
academic environments that have actually
been sitting around now for two
generations absorbing and up regulating
and creating an adaptive pathways for
the hyper optimization of the Mayan
virus getting infected with the mind
virus and so now we have a very powerful
mind virus which is spread throughout
most of blue culture it's you know hyper
present in most forms of media and all
people who participate in media it's
hyper present in finance it's hyper
present in sort of blue cities it's
hyper present in effectively everybody
who has a significant university
education who happens to be a strong
blew technology and you know it's it's
run amok right so that's happening
that's one big piece and I think Brett
Weinstein actually has done a pretty
good job from first-person experience
and as a background as an evolutionary
theorist and both noticing and
diagnosing this piece now here's the
next move when you encounter the mine
virus which is to say you interact with
other people who are infected by that
virus there's a few things that can
happen one is that the the the virus of
course wants to have as many host bodies
as possible so the primaries it tries to
get you to to become infected and it's
funny we even have another physical
architecture of those who are host
bodies in the mind virus requiring
people to bend the knee which is to say
to capitulate to becoming infected by
the mind virus which is a amazing visual
metaphor but that's what it's looking
for right it's looking to be
successfully transmitted as that as a as
an infection and then to take over the
host body and turn the host body into
its well its host body that's one two is
you can sort of not be infected
but then become engaged in the process
of fighting off the virus which largely
now looks a little bit like the
combination between like this sort of
rearguard action the moving backwards in
turn and like not be infected but also
not become in conflict with which shows
that this canceled culture and so I
think Joe Rogan right now is in the
process of being potentially cancelled
I'm certain that it's ramping up so what
happens is you encounter the virus you
either either join the board can either
become infected or you you know
increasingly unsuccessfully endeavor to
sort of fight off the infection as it
becomes more and more sophisticated at
doing one of two things either consuming
you or disempowering you like cutting
you off reducing your your capacity to
have agency so either it turns your
agency into its agency or remove your
agency or the third which is you have a
cytokine storm you have an autoimmune
response that is hyperactive and you've
become the alt-right as
my proposition is that we can say that
the alt-right is a cytokine storm
response to the mind virus and you know
history here we have to go back but I
would say the mind virus itself as a
response to something so I'm not what
ever happened in the 60s we're going to
leave that for now just talking about
what happened in the 90s and then since
then which has a sort of symmetric
characteristic rest of the cytokine
storm is a kind of mind virus but it's a
kind of mind virus which is optimized
for red monoculture and has the
characteristic of optimizing the other
direction and of course these two
viruses the cytokine storm and the mind
virus are irrevocably
in conflict because one of the things
that this virus does going back to the
beginning is plays on psyops it plays on
discourse it takes language and thought
itself in in your own head and with
other people and it predates on that its
primary milieu is a parasite on
narrative thinking speaking discourse
and relationship and so of course if
you're sitting over here in cytokine
storm land and you're sitting over here
in mind virus land the possibility of
discourse is effectively zero and
therefore of course the only plausible
thing to happen is is violence and
violence is the only solution the only
way of resolving conflict in an
environment of dialogue is no longer
vaguely possible and then if you're in
the middle now it happens it should be
set on both sides right on the one hand
you've got the mind virus which is
looking to either absorb your agency or
destroy your agency now you've got the
cytokine storm which is looking to
absorb your agency or destroy your
agency and both are in fact in cahoots
because both have more agency in their
in their collaboration and so the mind
virus and the cytokine storm while
inimicable
in existential contact conflict with
each other are actually in collaboration
in their mutual digestion of space
that's in between them until they
finally can come directly into contact
and there's nothing in between them and
then that of course will end in in
violence I'm probably quite massive
violence actually so so that's why
they're interesting now what I'd like to
do is take that frame which i think is
an
frame to hold and look at and say okay
how does that maybe square with this
other video which I think I'm titling
okay boomer and the niche of that
environment and is there a way for us to
think about how to respond to the
circumstances that we find ourselves in
that uses the insights that are here to
help us frankly thread the needle
because it's definitely a tricky place
to be